

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Full stack web developer looking for opportunities at a teamwork focused company which values staff development. With over 5 years experience mentoring, training and leading teams, I've developed strong soft skills making me a valuable team-player.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails (intermediate ↓)
- RESTful APIs, JSON, scraping
- Relational databases, SQL, Postgres
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- ES6 Javascript
- Git, Github, technical workflow
- Python (beginner ↓)
- React
- RSpec- Test driven development
- Wireframes, prototyping, UI

LANGUAGES

- English (Native)
- Japanese (JLPT N3)

CONTACT ME



deanabbott293@gmail.com



080 5545 9164



Yokohama, Japan



https://github.com/HundiBar



https://www.linkedin.com/in/dean-abbott/

HOBBIES

- Playing cricket in the Japanese Cricket League
- Cooking interesting dishes with sous-vide

DEAN ABBOTT

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER
RUBY ON RAILS | JAVASCRIPT | RSPEC

PERSONAL WEB PROJECTS

Midorin (Lead Developer)

https://www.midorin.one

A PWA which aims to be a one-stop-shop to allow you to become better at caring for plants.

Central Gaijin Library (Lead Developer)

https://cgl-hundibar.herokuapp.com

A book sharing platform to allow foreigners to source books for free in their native languages, while in Japan

Gaijin Eats (Full Stack - in progress)

https://gaijin-eats.herokuapp.com/

An application to map foreign eateries and supermarkets in Japan

EDUCATION

Le Wagon Tokyo - Batch #587

March 2021 - September 2021

24-week part-time intensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, Stimulus.js, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.

Money, Banking and Finance BSc(Hons)

University of Birmingham September 2009 - June 2012

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coding Bootcamp Teaching Assistant

Le Wagon | Sep 2021 - present

- Assist bootcamp students with coding challenges
- Ruby/ Javascript/ CSS

English Language Instructor

Interac (South Kanto) | May 2016- present

• Mentor teams of 10-15 teachers on best teaching practices

Berlitz (Kawasaki) | March 2020 - March 2021

• Delivering tailored lesson plans based on student experiences

Restaurant Shift/Assistant Manager

An Dining (Hokkaido) | November 2015 - March 2016

- Created new sequence-of-service handbook for staff training
- Trained all staff to follow new service practices

Gencerler Group (Brisbane) Nov 2013 - Dec 2014

- Managed teams of up to 30 staff with events up to 120 guests
- Responsible for ordering, staff scheduling and training